# Savannah Hammerton

#### GRADUATE STUDENT, EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS

University of Georgia College of Public Health

🗆 423 544 2453 | 🔀 savannah.hammerton@uga.edu | 🌴 smhammerton.com | 🖸 smhammerton | 🛅 smhammerton

## About

Graduate student working towards PhD in Epidemiology & Biostatistics (concentration in Data Analysis and Modeling). Particular interest and research emphasis in infectious diseases, infectious disease dynamics and modeling, and data analysis. Past experience in healthcare, providing strong contextual understanding of disease determinants, prevention, treatment, and outcomes, as well as an understanding of the real world implications of public health research and practice on individuals. This experience also drives context-aware data analytic approaches to answering epidemiological questions. Passionate and driven to build a career that benefits others.

# Education

University of Georgia Athens, GA

PHD EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS (DATA ANALYSIS & MODELING EMPHASIS)

2022-Present Athens, GA

MS EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS (EPIDEMIOLOGY EMPHASIS) | CERTIFICATE IN INFECTIOUS DISEASE EPIDEMIOLOGY

2020-2022

**Columbus State University** 

**University of Georgia** 

Columbus, GA

BS, HEALTH SCIENCE

2018-2020

Chattanooga College
DIPLOMA, PRACTICAL NURSING (SUMMA CUM LAUDE, DIRECTOR'S AWARD FOR CONSISTENT ACADEMIC AND CLINICAL

Chattanooga, TN

EVCELLENCE

2014-2015

# Relevant Experience

#### University of Georgia, Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics

Athens, GA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISANT

2022-Present

• Assist Dr. Andreas Handel in research for the Center for Influenza Vaccine Research for High-Risk Populations (CIVR-HRP) grant at the University of Georgia. Aid in research and data analysis on influenza vaccines, particularly data related to universal iinfluenza vaccine development.

## University of Georgia, Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics

Athens, GA

GRADUATE DEPARTMENTAL ASSISANT

2021-2022

 Assist in administrative departmental tasks, faculty retreats/meeting planning, and department event planning. Create and maintain spreadsheets on department classes, students, etc. Develop presentation materials and assist in orientation. Generate documents with information on degree programs, Graduate School processes, etc. Participate in research with Dr. Jose Cordero, planning and implementing a systematic review of environmental exposures and preterm birth.

## **Georgetown Behavioral Health Institute**

Georgetown, TX

LICENSED VOCATIONAL NURSE

2016-2016

• LVN working on adolescent male and female units, military unit. Conducted medication administration, milieu management, conflict resolution, patient chart management. Responsible for verbal de-escalation of agitated patients, medical complication and event management. Aided in coordination of care between all health care providers.

#### **Encompass Home Health Pediatrics**

Temple, TX

LICENSED VOCATIONAL NURSE

2016-2016

• Provided pediatric patient care for those needing 24-hour care or on hospice. Responsible for nutrition, hygiene, infection control, medication administration, respiratory status maintenance. Provided support to families of patients and socialization to patients throughout shifts.

# Research

#### Examining antibodies as correlates of protection against norovirus clinical outcomes

MS Thesis Project, Advisor - Dr. Andreas Handel

University of Georgia 2021-Present

#### Preterm birth and the environment

Research Assisantship, Dr. Jose

Cordero

University of Georgia 2021-2022

Prenatal exposure to flame retardants and adverse pregnancy outcomes: A systematic

Co-Author

University of Georgia 2021-2022

# Certifications\_\_\_\_\_

# **Social and Behavioral Research**

CITI Program 2021

#### **Epidemics - The Dynamics of Infectious Diseases**

Coursera 2020

#### **Certificate in Infectious Diseases and Disease Control**

Allegra Learning Solutions 2020

#### **Essentials of Public Health Research**

CITI Program 2019

#### **Research Involving Human Subjects**

CITI Program 2019

# Skills

#### **Data Analysis**

PRIMARY CODING LANGUAGE: R | ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE IN: SAS, STATA, SPSS

#### **Literature Searches and Management**

ENDNOTE, ENDNOTE CLICK, ZOTERO

#### **Laboratory Biosafety Level 2 Practices**

EXPERIENCE IN SAFE MICROBIOLOGY LABORATORY PRACTICES WHEN WORKING WITH HUMAN PATHOGENS

## **Infectious Disease Modeling**

Understanding of infectious disease modeling concepts, and experience in fitting infectious disease models

#### Organization

Skilled in managing multiple tasks and projects, maintaining high quality of work

#### Communication

EXPERIENCE IN CLINICAL, RESEARCH, AND PRIVATE GROUPS REQUIRING LARGE AMOUNTS OF COLLABORATION

#### **Health Education**

HAVE PROVIDED HEALTH EDUCATION IN BOTH CLINICAL AND NON-CLINICAL SETTINGS

# Leadership/Management

EXPERIENCE IN MANAGEMENT, LEADERSHIP OF MULTIPLE EMPLOYEES

# Organizations \_\_\_\_\_

Graduate Scholars of Epidemiology & Biostatistics (GSEB)

Secretary 2021-Present

Center for the Ecology of Infectious Diseases (CEID)

Member 2021-Present

Eta Sigma Gamma (ESG) | Health Science Honor Society

Member 2019-2020

**American Public Health Association (APHA)** 

*Member* 2019-Present

**Council of State and Territorial Epidemiologists (CSTE)** 

Member

2021-Present